zorinos.com 2019-12-25

# Privacy Policy - Zorin OS

We're committed to your privacy and protecting your personal information. This Privacy Policy aims to provide you with a clear explanation about how your information is collected and how we use it.

Zorin Technology Group Limited and its subsidiaries (“Zorin,” “Zorin Group,” “we,” “us,” or “our,”) collects information from you in different ways, from our websites, software (including “Zorin OS”), online applications, or other locations that refer or link to this Privacy Policy (collectively, our “Services"). While this Privacy Policy applies to all our Services, we also have provided certain specific privacy supplements that contain additional information about our practices in connection with particular Services. These supplements apply to your use of the Services they cover. Additional consent will be obtained for certain data processing activities. Information collected for or on behalf of the Zorin group of companies will be the responsibility of Zorin Technology Group Limited.

This policy (together with our terms of use and any other documents referred to on it) sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it. By visiting a Zorin website or using our Services you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this policy.

For the purpose of applicable data protection legislation, the data controller is Zorin Technology Group Limited (591652) of the Guinness Enterprise Centre, Taylor's Lane, Dublin 8, Ireland.

* * *

## Information we collect

We may collect the following types of information from you:

**Account registration.** When you register to use certain parts of our Services, we may ask for personal information such as your name, email address, age, and a password. We keep this information as so long as reasonably required to provide our Service.

**Newsletter.** When you subscribe to any of our newsletter mailing lists, we may ask for personal information such as your name, phone number, and email address. We keep this information as so long as you continue to consent to receive our newsletter and as so long as reasonably required.

**Payment information.** When you purchase a product from Zorin or make a donation to us, we may ask for information such as your name, email address, billing address, and credit card information. Credit card information is only used in processing your transaction and is not stored by us. Please note that we use the third party payment processors "Stripe Payments Europe, Limited" and "PayPal (Europe) Limited" to store this information and process your payments, while we use the services of "Concept Den Limited" to store order information (which does not include credit card information). We keep order information (which does not include credit card information, which may be stored by our payment processors) as so long as reasonably required to provide our Service and serve purchased products to the respective customers, or until you ask us to remove it.

**Forums and comment threads.** Any information that you disclose in these locations becomes publicly-available and may be recorded, archived, and republished by anyone. We keep this information as so long as you continue to consent to keep this information published.

**Information from third-party sources.** We may receive information about you from publicly and commercially available sources (as permitted by law), which we may combine with other information we receive from or about you. We also may receive information about you from third-party social networking services when you choose to connect with those services. We may notify you when we receive information about you from them and the purposes for which we intend to use that information.

**Other information.** You may choose to provide us with information when you contact us, respond to surveys, fill in forms, or use other features of our Services. We may keep a record of that information and/or correspondence. We keep this information as so long as reasonably required.

We may also collect the following types of anonymous and non-personally identifiable information from you in order to better understand how our Services are used and how to improve them:

**Online usage logs and analytics.** When visiting our websites or online applications, we may collection information about your interaction including but not limited to the device type, browser version, date & time of the site visit, referring website, pages visited on our websites, and visit duration. Please note that we may use a third party analytics service to collect some usage information from our websites and online applications. For more information about how we use cookies, please see the “Cookies policy” section below. We keep this information as so long as reasonably required.

**Error reports.** When you choose to send an error report in our software, it includes an anonymous unique identifier for your computer. The unique identifier does not identify you unless you (or someone acting on your behalf) discloses it separately.

**Census.** When using Zorin OS, your computer may send us a ping which only includes the number of users, an anonymous identifier for the installation, Zorin OEM partner batch (if applicable), and your OS version on an hourly basis. We use this information to count the number of active users of Zorin OS. The identifier is only used for the census (to prevent double-counting) and does not personally identify you unless you (or someone acting on your behalf) discloses it separately. Below is a sample of the contents of the ping:  
{id:"68f2d95b-f51f-4a5d-9b48-a99c28691b89", usercount:"1", oembatch:"", version:"15"}  
You may choose to disable these pings by selecting the "Don't participate in the census" option in the Zorin OS installer or entering this Terminal command after installing Zorin OS:  
sudo apt remove zorin-os-census

* * *

## How we use the information we collect

We may use the information we collect for the following purposes:

  * To register you for a Service.
  * To provide you with a Service, including to enable us to fulfill our obligations under any contract with you.
  * To process payments on our Services and send you goods.
  * To authenticate and enable access to Services and features of our websites for you.
  * To contact you to respond to enquiries.
  * To contact you to provide notices to you regarding your use of or the provision of our Services, or if your actions violate your agreement with us (if any).
  * To provide customer service and support.
  * To monitor business performance and for internal record keeping.
  * To personalise our Services to you.
  * To market our products or services to you. This may involve us calling you, where we have your phone number in order to do so (given your consent).
  * To administer referral programs, rewards, surveys, sweepstakes, contests.
  * To study how anonymous users interact with our Services.
  * To find errors in and analyse performance of our Services.
  * To improve existing Services and to aid the development of new products & services.
  * To comply with legal and regulatory obligations.
  * Otherwise with your consent.

We may use the information we collected to occasionally send you communications to inform you about new features, products & services, company news, solicit feedback, promotions & special offers, and other information which relates to our products or services or which we believe may be of interest to you. We may send such information by email, social networking websites, from within our websites or other Services, or any other method which becomes relevant from time to time. If you no longer wish to receive such communications from us, please follow the “unsubscribe” instructions provided in any of the communications, modify the communications preferences in your account or contact us using the contact details provided below.

You may choose to object to the any of the above methods of processing your information. If you would like to make any such request, please write to us using the contact details provided below.

* * *

## Access and control of this information

We don’t share your personal information with anyone outside our group of companies, except to provide you with services, products, to comply with the law, or to protect our rights.

**Service providers.** We use a variety of third party service providers to help us provide services related to our Services. Service providers may be located inside or outside of the European Economic Area (“EEA”). By using our services, you consent to transferring your data to these countries and to these service providers. For example, service providers may help us:

  * Process payments and/or store payment information.
  * Host our Services, as well as store information collected and/or used by our Services.
  * Provide customer service, communication, and marketing.
  * Provide analytics services.

These providers have limited access to your information to perform these tasks on our behalf.

**Other parties.** We may disclose your information to a third party as part of a merger or transfer, or in the event of a bankruptcy or sale of the company. Unless required by law, we will not otherwise share, sell or distribute any personal information you provide to us without your consent.

**Your rights.** Under EU data protection law, you have the right to request details of Personal Data which we hold about you. If you think that any information we have about you is incorrect or incomplete, or if you would like it to be removed, please write to us using the contact details provided below. We will correct or remove any information about you as soon as reasonably possible. You may also contact us to request the restriction of processing of your information stored by us by writing to us using the contact details provided below. We will comply with your request promptly and by no later than one month from receipt of any such request. We may charge a reasonable fee for dealing with your request which we will notify to you. If you would like to make any such request, please write to us using the contact details provided below.

**Age of consent.** By using our Services, you represent that you are at least the age of majority in your state or province of residence, or that you are the age of majority in your state or province of residence and you have given us your consent to allow any of your minor dependents to use these Services.

* * *

## How we protect your information

We are committed to protecting the confidentiality of the information we collect from you. We are constantly implementing and updating security measures – including administrative, physical and technical measures – to protect against unauthorised access, misuse, loss, modification or exposure of your information.

**Data retention.** We endeavour to retain personal information only for the period of time necessary for the purpose for which it was collected (for more information, see "Information we collect" above), or as required under any contract or by applicable law.

**Links to third-party products on our Services.** Our Services may link to third-party websites and services that are outside our control. We are not responsible for the security or privacy of any information collected by websites or other services. You should exercise caution, and review the privacy statements applicable to the third-party websites and services you use, as we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk.

* * *

## Cookies policy

We use persistent cookies to better understand how you use our websites and to allow us to provide a better user experience. These cookies remain on your computer after you close your browser and may be used by your browser on subsequent visits to our websites. You can choose to disable some or all cookies from your browser settings.

**Forums.** These cookies are used to keep you logged into your account during sessions and in between sessions, if you accept this option. In addition, cookies are assigned to store which forum topics you have read to inform you of this when browsing. [Forum privacy information](http://zoringroup.com/forum/ucp.php?mode=privacy)

**Google Analytics.** These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our website, which we use to help improve it. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited. You can opt-out of Google Analytics [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout). [Google Analytics privacy information](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245)

* * *

## Changes to this Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to modify this privacy policy at any time, so please review it frequently. Changes and clarifications will take effect immediately upon their posting on the website. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here that it has been updated, so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we use and/or disclose it.

* * *

* * *

## Your right to complain

If you have a complaint about the use of your information, you can contact the Data Protection Commission on [their website](https://www.dataprotection.ie/docs/Raising-a-concern/1716.htm) or write to them at the below address:

Data Protection Commission  
21 Fitzwilliam Square South  
Dublin 2  
D02 RD28  
Ireland
